Okay, with Councilman Matt Zall to make your way up. You know Matt Zall, who
was first elected to City Council in 2001, representing World of 15, who was
the group before the short way.
That's where he and his generation of the standard grow up. He's a strong
advocate for the arts, green building, alternative energy. Look what he's done
with Gordon Square.
He's chair of the Council Safety Committee. Last November, Matt got a national
honor. He was elected president of the National League of Cities.
And of course, he's making your balance now, he's responsible for the annual
Italian Heritage Month celebration for City Hall.
And Councilman Zall is going to induct Jim Craciun.
On behalf of the City of Cleveland, I can't think of two better ambassadors for
what makes Cleveland wonderful, the beautiful mosaic of people who call it home,
then Bill and then Dan and Debbie Hanson.
You two do a terrific job.
Father Guarval, thank you for the beautiful invocation. So I have to reciprocate
Chevronifac.
It means how are you, and the response would be good.
La Bulsana. Many years.
So Father Guarval, thank you for the beautiful blessing.
I do want to honor and recognize the former colleague of mine who I've worked
so much on in the international community, my former colleague, who's the
president, CEO of Cleveland Josephine.
And so it's my distinct honor and privilege to recognize somebody who has been
a mentor for me since I was probably a common Roman Catholic.
So following into the footsteps of his father to care for those in our
community who are grieving, I can't think of anyone better and kinder and gentler
than somebody like Jimmy Craciun.
It's such an admirable thing to do the following footsteps of your parents. And
Jim Craciun is a dedicated father of five.
His kids are here in the well, Jason, Jonathan, Jesse, and Nicholas. And he was
a loving and caring husband to the late mercy.
You know, Jim has always been a very deeply faithful person. He's been a
lifelong parishioner relating on carnival.
He's so involved in every aspect of what that church does. And his presence is
always known.
And in 1974, Jim's odyssey really began to unfold in his deeper appreciation
and love for his capital place, faith.
You know, risking his own life. Many people don't notice about Jim, but it's in
the book.
Jim smuggled violence and catechisms into Communist Romania. In 1974, he was a
young kid.
This is where he began his lifelong commitment to human rights.
And at the International Human Rights Conference in London in April of 1977,
Jim helped draft and signed a memorandum condemning the impact of the Helsinki
Accords and its lives on the Soviet Bloc countries.
You know, this same memorandum was prepared and signed simultaneously by
Romanian and Czechoslovakians by courageous dissidents who were later
imprisoned for this act.
He risked his life because he believed in the cause. All of us could only
follow our cause and say that I would put my own life before this issue just to
raise awareness.
So shortly thereafter, I began working at Croatia's uniform. And it was a great
job. I was a doorman. I learned how to say hello in about 15 different
languages.
And not only a doorman, I started carving parts. Jim came up to me and he goes,
"You're only 15. You don't have a job this life."
He's a regular people's guy. Like, "You don't have a job this life." But, you
know, Jim has always been like a big brother to me.
And he realized early on, with the recent passing of my father when I started
working there, that there wasn't a better way that could impact my life than
with giving me a job.
And it wasn't just a job. Jim took an active interest in my education and my
well-being. Jim got me involved in the Cleveland JC's.
He got me involved very active in the Holy Name Society of Our Lady Moncarmo.
In fact, I encourage you to run for office of that wonderful organization.
And Jim saw something in myself that I wasn't even aware of. He's been telling
me this for over 40 years.
He always said one day that I would one day rise to serve others. And I wasn't
quite sure at the time you know you're 15 years old what that phrase meant.
But he had a last-minute, still has a last-minute impact on my life.
So what I would first consider when running for city council, one of my first
meetings, of course, other than Basil Russo, was with Sue Krasner.
In fact, Jim served as my campaign chairman and he opened up many doors for me.
He still serves as my campaign chairman today.
I know, Jill, I have so much respect for you. And in the two minutes allotted
to me tonight, it's not adequate enough time for me to share with this
wonderful group tonight how much I love and respect you.
It's my honor and privilege to present for inductee into the Cleveland
International Hall of Fame, James Krasner.
So I feel like I'm giving an Academy Award. I want to thank the Academy. I
actually have the former inductees for voting, all of us unanimously.
To our guests, thank you for being here. I have been blessed with tremendous
mentors, just as Matt Hilton said that I've been a mentor of his.
I have been blessed with tremendous mentors. And I'd like to share with you a
few of them.
In fact, when you think about who my mentors were, according to Tom Brokaw,
they were the greatest generation.
My parents and all the people that were my mentors. I would begin with my
parents. We know that our parents are our first teachers in the home.
My dad had two Purple Hearts in World War II. My mother loved to embrace two
kids. She needs a Purple Heart too.
The other person who played a big part of my life was my parish priest. Being a
young boy at Lady Mark Arnold Church, Father Reno from Scotty,
who was the Renaissance priest, the visionary of our neighborhood, who began
the Detroit Shore Way.
And we're so lucky to have someone like Matt Zone continuing that effort to
take Detroit Shore's look down on the whole country as a model for how a city
should be in the neighborhoods.
That priest that was my mentor was the young seminary in the Navy before World
War II.
And he fought the ugly face of Fai Shih-Sih by Benito Mussolini.
When the war was over, the Communists thought that they would take over Italy.
And he fought the ugly face of communism.
And the communist infinity in Rome had a tree where my priest would hang
because of his fighting against them.
Of course we know the communist government never did take over, and we were
blessed to give Father Reno.
He's the man who asked me to smuggle violence into communist Romania.
And it should have been a long my life with all the work I did for human rights.
And I am privileged to have met such a priest.
Now I have to talk about another parish priest. Father Vasile Hanigan, the
Romanian Orthodox priest, I'm half Italian and half Romanian.
Father Vasile Hanigan, he had a church school when my brothers and I and my
sisters were young.
We had to go to Romanian school on Saturday. We had to go to the dance in
Romania, sing in Romanian,
speak in Romanian, and pray in Romanian.
And we didn't want to go to the Saturday services. But I'll tell you what,
today we're so happy that we had Father Vasile Hanigan.
He was also on the board of the International Services Center, which I have
served for many years.
And he pushed me to be on that board. So I bless his memory.
We have a pillar. You know, it's one thing to have something to say in your
community.
It's another thing to have somebody that will publish it in the plain view.
When the other man was our man, and we bless his memory.
Also we had in our community Peter Lukacs, who was the president of the, all
these people I get deceased.
So if I miss somebody, nobody can yell at me. They probably have one.
But anyways, Peter Lukacs was the publisher of the Romanian newspaper, the Olds
in America, called the America.
Cleveland is the oldest community, has the oldest community of Romanians in
America.
The first Romanian Orthodox Church, St. Mary's Romanian Orthodox Church, the
first Catholic Church, St. Amminas, and 65th,
both founded in the Detroit-Tillway neighborhood.
So we found out. Thank you.
So Peter Lukacs ran a paper that went all over the world.
And when we talked about what was going on in Romania during the horrible times
behind the Art Group, the Romanian people living under communism.
Mr. Lukacs gave me a platform. So I'm grateful to this very day and bless his
memory.
Next I'd like to remember some of the people in Cleveland that were my life.
My godfather, godmother. I'd have to say George Dobri.
Who made it, you know, George Dobri, into the Romanian community.
Beautiful man. Fought for our culture.
Another person, who some of you may not know, I remember Stella Zenoni.
What a princess in our Italian community.
And we have wonderful Italians now carrying that towards us, like Alberto Fidelity,
our basil Russo, Matt Zone.
Just a beautiful continuation of this beautiful Italian culture, which I'm
proud that my mother is out there.
I also want to remember some of those people that were on the board with me, I
get deceased.
Joe Holzer, who is the German Dornish Robin, who is who has worked, built out
the beautiful
Linnaud Pard on Columbia Road for the German people.
Joe Holzer was on our board, worked so hard. Bless his memory.
There's somebody here that's living out there. I read more.
I read more. Was on the board. She pushed me to be chairman of the board.
For the eight years I was the chairman, I read more.
It was towards me, every step of the way. I owe a lot to Irene Morrell.
Thank you, Irene Morrell.
I'd like to recognize, I'd like to recognize my brother Joe, who has been my
partner,
supported me through the years that I did, went to Paris, went to London for
human rights,
and also was on the board for so many boards, actually.
Joe was always there covering me at the funeral.
I want to honor my brother Jack, who spent 13 years in China, and has worked
with the
Chinese people and continues his work with China.
So I respect my brother Jack, and now three people were important to me,
and one of them is Bishop Anthony Pillow.
I was privileged to be on a first-name basis with Bishop Anthony Pillow,
and the honor of being the president of all the elite aid societies,
and the Catholic Diocese of Cleveland.
I am so blessed to have been a friend to Bishop Anthony Pillow.
I mean, here, I'm lucky we're the one million Catholics in this Diocese to have
such a shepherd.
Another person I'd like to thank is...
(applause)
Another person I'd like to recognize is Alex Maciaski.
I'm sorry he's not here, but he's been a tremendous mentor of mine,
and someone who made a young man feel like he was important.
I'd like you to read where we had that crazy Serbia that's published with Blake
Dieran,
who plays the... you know, the...
(inaudible)
And it's just one of us.
He cares about all of our nationalities.
And I see my great friend Abby Minna, Abdallah Minna, who is out there for you.
(applause)
Abdallah Minna, my hero, who straightened out all my understanding,
the standings of the Middle East.
Thank you, Abdallah. I love you.
And the next person I'd like to recognize is Sam Miller.
For 30 years, for all the organizations I had wanted to belong to and supported
and needed help, Sam Miller, the humanitarian, the philanthropist at this time,
he never refused me.
Never.
And you know what takes money to make this world operate?
I bless Sam, and I hope God grants him some good help.
Sam was a tremendous man over the last how many years here in Cleveland.
And now I'd like to tell you a little story about the International Services
Center.
We've reached out to refugees, and we're still doing it,
although I'm not sure what the board is for.
When the Kosovo War happened, we had some refugees from Albania.
There's a husband and a wife, two small children.
They came to Cleveland, and we got the husband with, in two days,
his job in the factory making $7.
We got the two children in public school.
We got them a house to live in, to pay rent.
We set up to pay rent for two months to help get on their feet.
After about a month and a half in Cleveland, United States,
I went to our offices.
We teach them English as a such a language.
So I ran into this obeying fellow, and I said, "How are you doing?"
And his English wasn't too bad, broken, of course.
He said, "I am doing wonderful.
I am now making $14 an hour."
I said, "Oh, my God, $14 an hour translates to $700 a week."
I said, "This is unbelievable. How did you do it?"
He goes, "The place where I work, higher than my wife."
John F. Kennedy said, and this is important at a time which the Syrian people
and some of the people are looking to America to help,
"John F. Kennedy, our great president said,
'The greatest asset that America has is its immigrants,
because they appreciate this country.'"
Now, the folks that like to say this, it has been written,
"For those that much has been given, much will be asked."
So if you can be a philanthropist like Sam Miller, continue to be charitable,
because our charities and our organizations, to make this town a great town,
they need your help.
If you're a young person and you're thinking about, you know,
you don't have a lot of money, but you've been given talents,
we need your talents.
We need your help. We need your support. We need your time.
Join some good charities and offer your time and talent.
The last thing I'd like to say, which I've based my whole life on,
learning from my parents, is that it isn't given that we receive.
Thank you.
[APPLAUSE]